{"Topic": "Human Anatomy (4 pages)", "Subject": "General Knowledge", "Data": [{"Question": "When we eat something we like, our mouth waters. This is actually not water but fluid secreted from", "op1": "nasal glands", "op2": "oval epithelium", "op3": "salivary glands", "op4": "tongue"}, {"Question": "Which of the following is known as the voice box?", "op1": "trachea", "op2": "pharynx", "op3": "epiglottis", "op4": "larynx", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Which one among the following will be absorbed fastest through the wall of digestive system?", "op1": "Black coffee as a hot beverage", "op2": "DDT taken as a poison", "op3": "Raw alcohol taken as a drink", "op4": "Ice cream as a desert", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "It has been observed the astronauts lose substantial quantity of calcium through urine during space flight. This is due to", "op1": "hypergravity", "op2": "microgravity", "op3": "intake of dehydrated food tablet", "op4": "low temperature in cosmos", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Cutting and peeling of onion bring tears to the eyes because of the presence of", "op1": "sulfur in the cell", "op2": "carbon in the cell", "op3": "fat in the cell", "op4": "aminoacid in the cell", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "The contractile proteins in a muscle are", "op1": "Actin and Myosin", "op2": "Actin and Tropomyosin", "op3": "Myosin and Troponin", "op4": "Troponin and Tropomyosin", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which of the following is not an enzyme?", "op1": "Amylase", "op2": "Pepsin", "op3": "Somatotropin", "op4": "Trypsin", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which one of the following is not a part of small intestine?", "op1": "Caecum", "op2": "Duodenum", "op3": "Jejunum", "op4": "Ileum", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "All enzymes are actually", "op1": "Carbohydrates", "op2": "Proteins", "op3": "Fatty acids", "op4": "Sterols", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Cartilage present in body is", "op1": "a muscular tissue", "op2": "an epithelial tissue", "op3": "a connective tissue", "op4": "a germinal tissue", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which one among the following glands is present in pairs in human body?", "op1": "Adrenal", "op2": "Liver", "op3": "Pancreas", "op4": "Pineal", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "During the process of respiration in human beings, the exchange of gases takes place in", "op1": "bronchi", "op2": "alveoli", "op3": "bronchiole", "op4": "pleura", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which one of the glands in human body produces the growth hormone (Somatotropin)?", "op1": "Adrenal", "op2": "Pancrease", "op3": "Pituitary", "op4": "Thyroid", "Answer": 3}, {"Question": "Which one of the following is a pigment?", "op1": "Albumin", "op2": "Elastin", "op3": "Keratin", "op4": "Melanin", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "In human beings, the opening of the stomach into the small intestine is called", "op1": "caecum", "op2": "ileum", "op3": "oesophagus", "op4": "pylorus", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "Cell or tissue death within a living body is  called as", "op1": "Neutrophilia", "op2": "Nephrosis", "op3": "Necrosis", "op4": "Neoplasia", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which part of the human eye is transplanted from a dead donor to a living person?", "op1": "cornea", "op2": "retina", "op3": "iris", "op4": "sclera", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "In the human body, nails are made up of", "op1": "melanin", "op2": "keratin", "op3": "enamel", "op4": "cartilage", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Sweating during exercise indicates operation of which one of the following processes in the human body?", "op1": "Enthalpy", "op2": "Homeostasis", "op3": "Phagocytosis", "op4": "Osmoregulation", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Pituitary gland is situated in", "op1": "The base of the heart", "op2": "The base of the brain", "op3": "The neck", "op4": "The abdomen", "Answer": 4}, {"Question": "In which part of the human body is the smallest bone found?", "op1": "wrist", "op2": "palm", "op3": "nose", "op4": "ear", "Answer": 1}, {"Question": "Which among the following is the largest endocrine gland of human body?", "op1": "Thyroid", "op2": "Parathyroid", "op3": "Adrenal", "op4": "Pituitary", "Answer": 2}, {"Question": "Which among the following is both an endocrine and exocrine gland of human body?", "op1": "Thyroid", "op2": "Pancreas", "op3": "Adrenal", "op4": "Pituitary", "Answer": 3}]}